um today I'm going to speak to you about
something that I hope will catch your
interest because the title of the sermon
today is God's favorite
track God's favorite track pray with me
please Heavenly
Father please speak to
us Lord I pray that you would hide me
behind the cross Lord that you would
speak through me Lord you know
how you know the message you want to get
across and so Lord
as I stand between you and the people
Lord in such a position that that causes
one to
tremble I pray Lord that you would speak
through
me and reach the hearts of your
people take this message Lord and make
it yours this is my prayer in Jesus name
amen I want to invite you to turn with
me to the Book of John chapter
[Music]
15 John the 15th
chapter we'll begin reading from verse
one John chapter
15 Jesus says here I am the True Vine
and my my father is the
husbandman every branch in me that
beareth not fruit he taketh away and
every branch that beareth fruit he
purgeth it that it may bring forth more
fruit now are you clean through the word
which I have spoken unto you abide in me
and I in you as the branch cannot bear
fruit of itself except it abide in the
vine no more can you except you abide in
me Jesus invites us to abide in him and
he says the end result of abiding in him
is that we will bear what much
fruit we will bear much
fruits the power of this truth abiding
in Christ and thus bearing fruit is
Illustrated in the story of Jesus as he
sends forth his 70
disciples so I'm going to invite you
again to come with me to the Book of
Luke Luke chapter
10 Luke chap
10 and I will again begin reading from
verse
one Luke chapter
10 verse one the Bible says and after
these things the Lord appointed un other
70 also and sent them two and two before
his face into every city and place with
he himself would
come therefore when he therefore he said
unto them the Harvest truly is great but
the laborers are what few pray ye
therefore the lord of the Harvest that
he would send forth say that with me
again that he would what send forth l
laborers into his
Harvest very interesting here that the
Bible tells us that Jesus sent these 70
ahead of him so that wherever he was
going to go they had gone before
him they had gone ahead of him in other
words the 70 had gone ahead to prepare
the way for Jesus
Jesus sent them basically saying the
places I am sending you to I am sending
you there to prepare the people to whom
you will be speaking for my coming for
my
message I want to share with
you that every time God invites you to
speak to someone I want you to think of
it this way it is because God is about
to manifest himself in the life of that
person
God sends you forward to work on behalf
of him so every time you're talking to
that neighbor or that coworker I want
you to think all right God obviously has
me speaking to this person because God
is about to manifest himself in this
person's
life you have a very important calling
and I want you to understand that this
group of 7D is a very powerful group
it's a very symbolic group and that's
what we're going to be looking at today
so the Bible says that Jesus uh uh calls
them and then sends them out and says
the the harvest is plenty but the
laborers are are
few jump down with me to verse
16 he that heareth you speaking to the
70 heareth who me and he that despiseth
you despises who me and he that despise
despiseth me despiseth him
that sent me pause for a second what is
Jesus doing
here he is showing the relationship
between the 70 and
himself he's saying in essence we are
one if they reject you they have
rejected me and if they reject me they
have rejected my
father what a beautiful thought that
Jesus would connect himself so
intimately with his people with his 70
that he says hey you and I are
one now notice verse
17 the Bible says and the 7 returned
again with with Joy saying Lord even who
the devils are subject unto us through
thy name
let me ask you a question what was the
witnessing experience of this group of
70 did they have a powerful witnessing
experience did God use them in such a
way that even the Devils were subject
onto them how many of you would like to
live life with Devils subject to you
with demons subject to you how many of
you would like to live the kind of life
that the 70 lived they rejoiced in the
power that God had given them and God
said to them you and I are what are one
just as you are one with me so you are
one with my father through
me notice something else about the 70
the 70 were connected with a
harvest the Harvest is plentiful but the
laborers are few that's what he told the
70 in other words they were sent forth
to gather in a
harvest let me read it in your hearing
Mark 4: 26-
28 he said unto them so is the kingdom
of God as if a man should cast seed into
the ground and should sleep and Rise
night and day and the seed should spring
for spring and grow up and he knoweth
not how for the Earth bringeth forth
fruit of herself first the blade then
the ear after that the full corn in the
air but when the fruit is brought forth
immediately he putteth in his sickle
because the Harvest is
come what is the purpose of the
70 they are to gather in the the harvest
let me ask you a question what do you
think your work
is it's the same it's to gather in the
Harvest therefore I want you to
understand that this group of
70 that Jesus initially sends out it is
the first group he sends out besides the
12 we'll read a little bit later that
just one chapter
earlier Jesus sent the 12 disciples and
pretty much said to them the same thing
he said to the
70 so on one hand he sends the 12 on the
other hand he sends 70 but I want you to
understand that this group of
70 has a lot to do with who God wants
you and I to be today
Luke
10:2 I read it again therefore he said
unto them the Harvest truly is great but
the laborers are few pray ye therefore
the lord of the Harvest that he would
send forth laborers into the
Harvest send
forth the term send forth the word send
forth it literally means to shoot out
the word is translated over 40 times in
the New Testament as cast
out it's almost used uh in a violent
sort of
way when Jesus talks about demons being
cast out he's using the same word when
the Bible talks about uh uh the the
people who cast out the son in the
parable and said let us take his
inheritance it's the same word being
used it represents something being
violently Thrust out and Jesus says pray
the Lord that he would send
forth cast
out
laborers that that
word in a very literal sense it means
this to lead one forth or away somewhere
with a force that he cannot
resist when God God says to us I want
you to go forth he he's expecting that
that the force of his word and of his
love is so great that we
cannot
resist you remember Jeremiah 20:9 where
Jeremiah is speaking he said then said I
I will not make mention of him nor speak
anymore in his name speaking of God but
his word was in my heart as a burning
fire shut up in my bones and I was weary
with forbiding and I could not stay in
other words Jeremiah saying I could not
resist the Lord I was compelled to share
his
word beloved we ought to be the same
way God is compelling us to go out into
the field why because the Harvest is
ripe that the IPL these 70
disciples were sent forth to do
something very specific they were sent
forth to
Bear
fruits the
Harvest I'm sending you out to gather in
Fruit I'm sending you out to Bear fruits
and the question is how would they bear
fruit come back with me hold your place
here and notice with me John chap
15:5 because there Jesus says I am the
what Vine and you are the branches he
that abideth in me and I in him the same
bringeth forth much fruit for without me
you can do how much nothing if you abide
in me and my words abide in you you
shall ask what you will and it shall be
done unto you so Jesus saying if my
words abide in you all right now listen
carefully guys Jesus wants his word to
abide in
you so that means that his word should
be
where in
you if his words are in
you and upon on
you what does that make
you it makes you
attract not feeling me man y are not
feeling if God's words are written upon
you what does it make you
come on
guys it's time to
Glow beloved listen to me these tracks
are good good
tracks They I love these
tracks and these tracks contain truth
amen but but there's a problem with
these tracks you see sometimes you might
give a person a track oh you know what
alcohol why not when the person is not
struggling with
alcohol but hey I gave a
track or or you might give a track where
is God when I'm hurting when the person
has not experienced that kind of pain
he's rich and increased with Goods with
need of
nothing so sometimes we run into the
issue of how do I share how do I know
what to share to a person be if I don't
know that
person so God says listen I'm going to
make you a trap
a a smart
track that means this track can assess
the situation and know okay ah I know
what this person
needs and because you have internalized
the word of God into your heart you
don't necessarily need one of these in
your
pocket you can be the
track gods
favorite
track happens to be
you so so listen carefully the 70
represent a group of no no no no come
back come back John 15 verse 17 verse 7
we didn't finish reading if you abide in
me my words abide in you you shall ask
what you will and it shall be done unto
you now notice verse 8 herein is my
father what glorified
that you bear much fruit so shall you be
my disciples so how is the father
glorified by us doing what bearing fruit
but the only way we can bear fruit is by
abiding in him and having his word what
written upon us so these 70 represented
a group of people who were abiding in
the
vine what were
they be 70 represented
what think if Christ is the
vine these 70 represented the the
branches what did they represent
everyone the
branches Jesus said my father is
glorified when you bear much fruit that
is when you are abiding in me now now
now I want you to notice come with me to
Matthew chap 5:14 Matthew 5: 14 because
Jesus said the same thing but he used
different language in Matthew chap 5
beginning with verse 14 notice what he
said Matthew 5:14 are you ready the
Bible says here ye are the what light of
the world a city set on a hill cannot be
hid verse 16 or verse 15 neither do men
light a what a candle and put it under a
bushel but on a candlestick that it may
give light unto all that are in the
house let your light so shine before men
that they may see your good works and
glorify your father which is in
heaven let your light
shine very interesting uh
um Jesus said let your light shine
and then he Compares letting your light
shine to glorifying God but this time in
Matthew 5 he says you are the light of
the world you are like a
candle a candle what everyone
Candlestick see here's what we need to
answer this morning why did Jesus send
out
70 why not
75 why not 80 why not
why 70 listen listen
listen remember when the disciples came
back and said even the demons are
subject unto us through thy what through
thy name through th name listen listen
Isaiah 59: 19 listen to what the Bible
says here so shall they fear the name of
the Lord from the West and his glory
from the rising of the sun when the
enemy shall come in like a flood the
spirit of the Lord shall lift up a
standard
against him the name of the Lord is
synonymous with the glory of the Lord so
the disciples bore the glory of the Lord
or the light of the Lord they let their
light shine which means it's just
pointing right back to the fact that
they were in fact like a
Candlestick a what
everyone now when I say
Candlestick you should be thinking
Candlestick okay no one call that just
now when I say
Candlestick you should be thinking Old
Testament Sanctuary because you remember
that in the Old Testament God had
instructed Moses to build a sanctuary
and within the sanctuary there was an
article of furniture called the seven
Branch
Candlestick come with me to the Book of
Exodus chapter 25
Exodus chapter
25 and while you're turning there and
you need to to have this refreshed in
your mind this group of 70 represented
those that were bearing fruit they were
connected to the light and they were
connected to the preaching of the word
they were represented as one with the
father and the son and they were how
many in
all 70 listen Exodus 25:31
the Bible says here and thou shalt make
a Candlestick of pure what gold of
beaten work shall the Candlestick be
made his
shaft that shaft would be the stem of
the
Candlestick and the base and these were
actually two separate parts there was
the base there was the stem and
then reading
on uh the I'm sorry um his shaft his
branches his bowls his knops and his
flowers shall be of the same shall be of
the what everyone shall be of the same
verse 32 and six branches branches shall
come out of the side of it three
branches of the Candlestick out of the
one side and three branches of the
Candlestick out of the other side now
that term shall come out is the Hebrew
word
yatsa shall come out shall spring forth
listen carefully
beloved Jesus giving instruction of the
of the Candlestick says that there was
one Center branch one Center Vine one
Center
stem and out of that stem came six
branches
I am the
Vine I am the stem and you are the what
branches that were shooting forth out of
the
stem God says when you are connected
with me there is only but one option for
you and that is you shoot
forth you go out bearing fruit now
remember what he said every branch that
does not bear fruit evid is that that
branch has not been
connected to the
vine
so Exodus 25:33 reads
this three
bowls made like unto
almonds fact let me go back to verse
32 verse 32 reads this
Exodus 25:32 is it on the screen six
branches shall come out of the side of
it three branches of the Candlestick out
of the one side and three branches of
the Candlestick out of the other side
verse
33 three bowls made like onto almonds
with a knop and a flow in one branch and
three bowls made like onto almonds in
the other Branch with a knob and a
flower so in the six branches that that
came out of the Candlestick now how many
of you like math
how many of you hate
math okay you're going to have to bear
this part listen guys don't don't let
your mind shut down all right let me
explain how many branches in the
Candlestick six and
then the vine the stem okay in these six
branches in one branch we're just going
to take one branch in one branch there
was to be a a an almond
followed by a knop followed by a flower
and what it represented was the stages
in which fruit
blossoms right so so in one branch there
was to be three sets of these so three
sets of three in one branch how many is
that in a
branch how many is
that
three times
three that would be nine ornaments in
one branch are you with me nine
ornaments in one branch
now
um how
many how many
branches these were to take place in how
many of the branches in the no no no not
seven in the six branches follow me
carefully guys six branches so six 6 * 9
is what 54 hold that number what number
everyone 54 okay now notice with me
verse 34 Verse 34 so in the Candlestick
shall be now when the Bible says in the
Candlestick what it's saying here is
that in the center Branch so we just
looked at the six branches and there
were three sets of these of these uh uh
almonds knops flowers making 54 now in
the can stick itself the center Branch
there shall be four bowls made like unto
almonds with their knobs and their
flowers so four sets instead of three
the center had four which would be how
many how
many four sets of three four
time three 12 very good very good so
check this out
guys between the branches the six
branches and the center Branch there
were then a total of how many
ornaments
54 +
12 54 plus what is how
much how
many 60
Psalm
11915 Thy
word is what is a lamp unto my feet and
a light unto my
path what were these 70 to go forward
with the
word beloved they were to go forward
with the word of God and as long as they
were abiding in the word and the word
with them they had power they had
Authority Beloved the Candlestick is the
original glow
track Thy word is a lamp to my feet in
fact in Isaiah 5511 Jesus said so shall
my word be that goeth forth
yat suits
out so shall my word be that go goeth
forth out of my mouth it shall not
return unto me void but it shall
accomplish that which I please and it
shall prosper in the thing where to I
sent it so here's my question for you
the seven Branch Candlestick what does
it
represent the word of God are you
sure I want a different answer now the
seven Branch Candlestick what does it
represent no no no no what does it
represent Jesus said you are the what
light of the world a city set on a hill
cannot be hidden neither do men light a
candle so so according to Jesus the
seven Branch Candlestick
represents the people but hold on wait a
minute the seven Branch Candlestick were
Al also told represents
the the word of
God so you mean the Candlestick is both
the people and the word of
God wait a minute so if I am the
candlestick
then that
means not only am I to be the
light I am also to be the
word God's favorite
tra you see beloved it's not just enough
for us to embrace the word what I'm
trying to tell you this morning is that
God wants you to be the
word hold on do you remember we said
that Jesus sent out the 70 in one
chapter earlier he sent out the 12 now
let me ask a question what does the 12
remind you of in the
sanctuary the table of sobre right and
why do we say that because there were 12
tribes of Israel or and 12 disciples and
how many loaves of bread on the table 12
okay so watch this guys what does the
table of showbread represent
then you just jumped someplace else we
just said the 12 that number 12 points
us to
who the people of God but wait a minute
Jesus also says man shall not live by
bread alone but by every word that
proceeds out of the mouth of God so
watch this the table is so represents
the people of God but it also represents
the word of God by the way how many lows
on the
table in how many
rows two so there was
six and
six I'm not
feeling there was
six and
six
yeah just as the table just as the
Candlestick represents the word of God
so the table of showbread represents the
word of God and both of those represent
you and I as his people which means
God's trying to tell us not only do I
call you to be the light I call you to
be the
word beloved there's a reason why Jesus
is calling us to
be the
word because you see
Heaven and Earth shall pass
away y'all not
feeling but Satan has no power or
authority
over the
word you you understand that that when
when Jesus came to this world the Bible
says in John 111 that that that that uh
in the beginning was the what was the
word and the word was
with God and the Word was God so John
1:14 says that word came into this world
and that word became what flesh so what
did Jesus send to this what did God send
to this world he sent a glow track y not
feel he sent the
word and the word listen carefully
Beloved the word became
flesh now why would the word do that
Beloved the word did that so that
flesh could
become the
word the word became flesh that flesh
might become the
word love listen to me this is crazy
because Jackie actually stole part of my
sermon without even knowing it
Jesus said I am the light of the
world and then he said you are the light
of the
world wait
what I thought he was lot no no no he
says look I am the light of the world
and if you are connected with me then
you are the light of the
world listen listen
listen the world tried to destroy the
word of God
God you you understand what I'm saying
when Jesus came to this
earth and the Jews said okay the leaders
said okay HH uh we don't like Jesus what
they were saying was we don't like the
the
word so you know what they try to do
with the
word we're going to spit on the word
we're going to mock the word we're going
to beat the word we're going to try to
try to change the word word we're we're
going to crucify the word we're going to
bury the word but beloved Heaven and
Earth may pass away but the word of God
stands
forever therefore beloved if you want to
be Invincible like Jesus was invincible
become the
word he's telling you become the word
you say Pastor become the word that
doesn't even make any sense yes it does
because the Bible says as a man thinketh
in his heart so is he that's why Jesus
said I'm going to write my words in your
heart so if my words are in your heart
and that is what you are thinking you
become the
word become the
word right don't just possess the word
become the word
become
love don't pray Lord Give Me Love pray
Lord Make Me
Love become love become Joy become peace
become longsuffering Jesus wants you to
so much identify with his character and
his word that it is as though you and he
are
one
one that's why the Bible says Thy word
have i hidden my heart that I might not
do what sin against
you second Corinthians 3:2 let's put it
up on the screen 2 Corinthians chapter
3:2 notice what the Bible says here cuz
some of you thought man Pastor making
this up we can't really be the word well
how about
this
you are our
what Epistles written in our hearts
known and read of all men hold on guys
when people look at you do you realize
that they are reading a
track now there are different tracks and
different
authors so the question is when people
look at
you what are they
reading what are they seeing about God
when they look at you when they read you
are they going yes I don't want
God we are Epistles let's keep going
verse
three for as much as you are manifestly
declared manifestly declared to be the
Epistle of Christ ministered by US
Written not with ink but with the spirit
of the Living God not in tables of stone
but in the fleshy tables of the heart
you are God's writing you are God's
tract become the
track know that every person that you
come in contact with every person that
you interact with you don't have to have
a track to be like oh man I couldn't
witness be the
track what does that mean Pastor okay
you know what I want you to get all
these tracks
here talking about Smart Tracks right so
we get all these tracks and you know
what we're going to do we're going to
read these tracks and we're going to
internalize them them we're going to
actually know these tracks so that if I
run into someone who has an health issue
I can become the health track oh yeah
did you
know right if I'm if I'm meeting someone
who wants to know about the law of God
oh yeah I got it written here so oh
guess what you may not have it all
perfectly memorized but you have so a
filled yourself with the word of God
that at any moment you can become any
track to anyone
God wants you to be you are the new
trap you are the glow
trap become the trapped that's what God
is calling us to do that's what God is
calling us to be now now how many
ornaments did we say so far 66 but it
doesn't stop
there check this out by the way how many
branches all all together seven do you
remember in the Book of Revelation how
Jesus was walking in the midst of seven
golden candlesticks and he says that
these seven candlesticks represent the
whole the entire New Testament Church
from his time all the way down to the
end of time what branch are we in now
we're in the last Branch the seventh
Church beloved what I'm trying to share
with you is that each one of those
churches bear the responsibility of the
we are supposed to be going forward in
the power of the 70 saying man even the
devils are subject to us because we're
doing everything in your name we are
reflecting Your Glory we are abiding in
the
vine second Peter chapter 1 verse 19
notice what the Bible says here 2 Peter
chapter 1 verse 19 okay guys buckle up
because this is about to get really
really really really really serious
second Peter chapter 1: 19 we have also
a more your word of what prophecy where
unto you do well that you take heed as
unto a what light that shineth in a dark
place until the day Dawn and the day
star arises in your heart so the Bible
tells us that the light also reflects
what
prophecy so come with me beloved because
I want you to see something
here in Exodus 25 and verse 35 notice
what the Bible says Exodus 25 and verse
35 how many ornaments so
far 66 but then God lays out something
else in verse 35 he said and there shall
be a knp under two branches of the same
and a knp under two branches of the same
and the knp under two branches of the
same according to the six branches that
proceed out of the Candlestick so along
with the 66 ornaments God now says at
the Connecting Point of each of the six
branches in other words here's two
branches here's two branches here's two
branches I want you to put a knot
connecting two branches a KN connecting
two branches a knob connecting two
branches so now instead of 66 we
have
69 how many
branches how many
branches how many branches Al together
how many seven branches I got a question
for you what is 7 time
69 4 what
483 does that number ring a bell to
anyone do you understand that in the
Book of Daniel a prophecy was
given and this prophecy stated that 69
sevens would pass or
483 years before the anointing of Jesus
Christ as the
Messiah Beloved the seven Branch
Candlestick points us to the light of
the world which is Jesus Christ not only
as who he was the light of the world but
prophetically speaking John the Baptist
is at the Jordan and he's preaching a
message of rep
repentance repent why because the axe is
laid to the root of the what of the
what of the
tree of the what
everyone the tree every Branch every
what everyone branch that does not bear
fruit is going to be cut down he's
talking about the
Candlestick the six 69 week prophecy
beloved points us to what you and I
should be preaching as the light to this
world Jesus Christ his baptism on our
behalf the Redemption that he brought
into the world as a result of his
baptism but it doesn't stop at 69 weeks
guys because
listen Not only was there these
additional knocks in the center of the
Vine
but
remember the Candlestick was upon a
base so the
base the
ornaments and the
knobs all come out to
70 how many
branches seven I got a question for you
what is 70 time 7
the Candlestick was a prophecy of the
coming of Christ of the work of Christ
of the death burial resurrection of
Christ as the light of the world and God
says listen you are now the light of the
world you are those 70 why did he choose
70 because you're my
Candlestick you're the light that I'm
sending into the
world and the message you are the glow
track and the message you're to bear
you're to Bear Christ and him
crucified you're to Bear Christ and him
lifted up on the cross you're to Bear
the message of Christ and his work of
redemption his work of of forgiveness
that's what I want you to
Bear you are the
Trap love let me share with you one more
thing and then we're going to close it
out the base the stem grew out of the
base did you catch what I just said the
stem grew out of the base who is the
stem let me ask you where did Jesus come
forth from where did he come forth
from he came forth from his
father the base
the
stem and then the
fire the
base and then the
stem and then those
seven fires
burning do you know what those fires
represent the Holy Spirit
beloved Jesus said that it was through
the holy spirit that he and his father
would become one with us that seven
Branch Candlestick represents the
Oneness you want to be one with
me you want to be
one bear
fruit abide in me be my trap